[Music]
Welcome to busy central launch event
20125 release day one. And in this
session we will show you one new amazing
functionality and this is new copilot
related to
sustainability. Okay let's see why was
this copilot added at all. So let's look
what we have and what we had and what we
have in this moment related to
sustainability.
How you can post uh entries related to
sustainability? You can use
sustainability journal or from this wave
general journal or purchase invoice if
you have total emissions uh from some
external source. If you do not have uh
total emissions, you can use only
sustainability journals in combination
with emission factors and embedded
formulas. But now we have some
challenges.
Challenges are that most emissions again
do not have uh total amounts already
ready. So you will not get them for
example for your hotel stays for uh your
flight for your uh usage of car of truck
you do not have ready total emissions
and then finding all these uh emissions
and adding the library or actually in a
uh sustainability subcategories. It
require to to find emission factor
source of auditing and this is complex.
You need to open every time subcategory
by subcategory to enter uh this
information even if you can find but
even to get them this is not easy. So
what we wanted to do we wanted to make
it easier with copilot as always what
copilot can do copilot can calculate
total emissions update emission factors
if you want it and add source for
auditing. What does it mean? If you want
in some cases you want when first time
when you get uh calculated emissions you
want to update for the future emission
factor. So you will not uh use LLM every
time uh for the same uh source. But in
some situations you do not want because
you will use only only one account for
different uh values. So system will not
update emission factor. This is on you.
You can set up how you want to this uh
system to behave. So let's look in a
copilot process flow but please do not
be surprised how complicated it is
because this is not complicated. We just
wanted to show you all small details how
system is working because this is a
complex job um uh under the
hood. Okay we will start with
sustainability journal. We do not have
emissions and you need to enter some
information actually the same
informations as you are using if you
want to use formulas account name line
description country code if you have
different from uh your company
information if you if this is the same
uh country system will use from company
information then some values uh what you
will use about fuel about distance
whatever you want to add but what is
crucial here crucial is your line
description system needs to understand
what you want to collect so this is not
enough to say car you need to explain
which car so system will find proper uh
emission for this car okay then we will
run copilot when we run copilot first
for system we will check is there
already emission factors uh in a system
so if we have emission factors it will
be showed in a copilot prompt as
automated suggestion so that's good
system will not run lm system will take
it as we already have calculated and
that's it but if there is No emission
factor in a line. This is a uh question.
So system will use LLM to find matching
with your uploaded files. We will
explain later what does it mean uploaded
files. If we find match good system will
use emission factors from the from this
file embedded formulas and when we
finish system will get a recommended
suggestion and proper source file
description from this file. So you will
have everything necessary for auditing.
If something is missing, we will have
pre-processing contextual warning. So
system will find what is missing and you
will get uh some warning what you need
to improve in the system. So this is if
we have in a file but now imagine we do
not have a file or system couldn't find
the file what's the system will uh work
further system will try to find some
somewhere publicly this information and
if you find the match for this uh line
and lines system will again add in the
same recommended suggestion but this
time source will be public
information. Okay. What you can do as
optional step if you have for example in
our file two or three match so system
couldn't decide instead of you you can
maybe update description and then
regenerate or maybe you can choose one
of these two or three options maybe it
will be easier for you you can decide
which one you want to apply. So this is
optional step to make it better for the
usage.
Then system will update all these values
in a sustainability journal because you
made some changes if you made some
changes description and some other
values and proceed with the
posting. What we will get? We will get
calculated emissions in our journal. So
you will have ready sustainability
journal and then as I mentioned if we
wanted to have updated emission factor
system will update emission factor for
future usage. If no nothing and then
when you post system will update
emissions sustainability journal we will
post and everything will be fine.
Perfect. But as I said this is really
complicated on the first site but what
is here for you as a user. As I said I
wanted to show you how complicated it is
because there are different combination
even a little bit more than that. I try
to simplify this chart uh what is
happening under the hood. But in general
what do you need to do? You need to run
your sustainability journal to provide
proper description and run copilot. When
you get suggestion, you need to review
and you need to post and that's
it. Okay. How to prepare uh emission
factors? Uh for emission factors again
as I mentioned we can option we have a
option to upload uh
files. What you can do? You can prepare
Excel file. You can find public
information from different sources from
different countries because the most of
countries are publishing this uh
information somewhere and the most of
these information are in Excel already
in Excel. If they are not you need to
move to Excel but if they are you can
find them you can. Our suggestion is to
cut and to organize in some specific
columns because uh it can be a huge
document and system cannot you know
system will try to find hours and hours
to to to connect uh all of them to match
all of them. So our suggestion is to cut
them what you really need and then
upload. What you can do with the
uploads, you can use different types of
uploads because
um you can upload for example one for
one main for your country.
Then you will get for example you have
100 cars from one the same manufacturer
and you can get table with emission
factor from this car manufacturer or
track manufacturing. So you can have
specific for some specific brand
information then you can get with the
from flight company you are traveling
the most their emission factor. So you
can combine and system will all the time
use all of them to find the best match.
So if system find is specific uh brand
track or car system will find in this
file. If no system will try to find what
is a common for or um comp or cars or
trucks in your country and this is if
you have files our recommendation is to
have files because it will be much
easier for you to work with
that okay what we can do
further uh you can create a line and
after that you can upload file and
that's it you can use as I said by
country by type and um keep only
important information and what
If you have obsolated information, you
can easily mark this line and remove
this file. So you will not handle this
obsolete information because in some
situation uh information are changing
from year to year and you can upload new
one. So you can easily handle with
uploading the deleting files without any
problems. So that's it what I wanted to
show you before going directly to demo.
So now my colleague Arthur will show you
how it works a practice. As I said this
is not complicated as looks like in a
flowchart. You can see how it is easy
when we are using a demo. Arthur uh
thank you Alexander for introduction. Uh
I'm going to start my demo straight from
the sustainability journal. Uh as all
the setup for this copilot is already
done. Uh in this uh journal batch you
can see uh the mix of different
categories uh for the cars, hotels and
aeroflights and you can notice a new
action calculate CO2. Uh this is the
co-pilot action. Uh I'm going to click
it and then explore the
results. Okay. So on this page you can
find a lot of information. Let's start
from top. Uh you can see that copilot
suggested six lines out of six and the
confidence is 100%. It means everything
was very accurate. Uh and let's uh
explore the subpage. On the subpage the
first field uh is a source as Alexander
mentioned. Uh there could be two options
either the uploaded file to business
central or the public information. Uh
what you can do you can um drill down
this is field and for the average petrol
car we can see that copilot was able to
find the right match. This is the petrol
car. Uh source description indicates uh
the name of the file. Uh there's the
high confidence for this uh match and
the emission factor is taken from the
file. for the second line which is the
diesel car. I also want to drill down
the source fields and another match.
This is the diesel car. Same file and
the other mission
factor. Um for the third line which is
the uh condos car. Uh you can notice
that the file is different. Uh so this
is the the file with the cars only and
the match is also right. This is exactly
the category of this car.
Um now you can also notice that the
hotel star hotel stay uh we got two
lines one line got source and the other
one public information. The reason for
that that the second line or the hotels
this is not for the UK this is for
Germany and since our file is only for
UK uh copilot didn't consider this file
for Germany. It means that there's no
match from the available sources and uh
the information is taken uh from the
public. Uh and then for the last line
airflight uh also the perfect match uh
short flight from to UK uh as also
defrag file and we got the emission
factor. Perfect. We have all the
emission factors. We can also scroll a
little bit on the right. We can see the
final values of emission factor. Uh now
what we also can take a look we can
drill down the copilot suggested field.
Uh where we have six out of six lines
and here extra information. So besides
the emission factor and fields uh taken
from the journal on the bottom page we
have the calculation explanation. So for
each line we have the formula uh for
calculation uh the values and the final
result for the car. The formula is
simple distance traveled multiplied by
emission factor distance traveled taken
from the business central emission
factor taken from the file and the final
result matches emission CO2 column. Uh
for example for the hotel stays the
formula is a little bit different.
Instead of distance we have number of
hotel stays. Uh this information is also
taken from business central number of
nights and multiply by mission factor
from the file. Uh for airflights it's a
little bit different. There is no
distance in business central only the
route and copilot was able to calculate
the distance. uh since this is the round
trip so we are talking about the
distance from London to Frankfurt and
back to from Frankfurt to London. Pilot
summarizes uh the distance to the total
distance and then we have total distance
multiplied by emission factor final
value everything is accurate. Great. So
after I verify everything with
calculation explanation I can close this
window and I want to keep the results. I
click
EIT and when I do this the information
is saved here in the emission CO2 and
also in the um uh account category. Now
everything is perfect here because I
have a good description in the line. Uh
but let me show you the other batch when
there are some issues with the way um
how description are specified or the
other uh information is not accurate. I
want to click calculate CO2 and then
explain uh what is all
about. Okay. Uh so the first line is uh
highlighted differently. Let's see why.
If you scroll to the right uh there is a
number of warning fields. We can drill
down to this field and we can see that
more than one emission factor found in
the file. Okay, we have this warning.
But how we can actually see uh this is
the source fields that I've already
presented. If you drill down to this
one, we can see that there are multiple
different categories. And the reason is
that because our description is not
accurate. It only says motorbike and it
matches different categories. Uh what we
can do, we can actually choose a
specific line and then we can click okay
and choose a specific a specific
category, a specific emission factor.
But this is something that we don't want
to do. We want to improve our
description to make a really accurate
match. So I want to click cancel here
and I want to update description. For
that I need to drill down to copilot
suggested field and here I can update uh
my description without getting back to
journal right from here. Uh so I want to
say okay this is actually large
motorbike not any other one. I want to
close this page. Description uh is here.
And I want to click regenerate to
actually get the right match. I click
regenerate. And now you can see that the
line is highlighted in green. On the
right side, there is no warning.
Emission CO2 is
calculated. And if I drill down to the
source field, I have only one match more
by large. This is exactly what I have in
description. So now with this uh
correction in description uh we have um
a better uh result from copilot. Now for
the second line you can see that there
is no source and there is a warning
here. Uh if I click it I can see the
distance is not provided. Uh yeah so
there's only unit of measure for this
line but no distance and that means that
this line is not passed to the copilot.
So we only have one line out of two
suggested for copilot.
And that concludes my demo. Back to you,
Alex Arthur. Thank you, Arthur, for this
great demo. So, you can see how good
Copilot can be and how big improvement
in uh collecting all emissions with
sustainability can be done with copilot.
Now, just few things before we close
this session. Availability
um this copilot will come in 26.1 or
two. So we are currently completing uh
this functionality and in this first
release it will be delivered as a public
preview as all our copilot features. So
every time first release is public
preview in this moment we have
officially support only for English
language. It doesn't mean it cannot work
in other languages in during our test we
tested a bit other languages. So
probably it can work and it can provide
good information in other languages but
officially we support in this release
English language only and what is now
ongoing effort so we want to continue uh
investment in this copilot in next wave
or waves depends uh how it's going
minimum we want to improve some specific
areas we found in the meantime uh during
building this copilot so we want to
improve some specific areas we want to
prepare everything for gen availability
so It should be G as soon as possible
and idea is to enable support for other
languages especially uh sustainability
reporting will be uh will exist in many
different countries. So we want to
support as more languages as possible in
this moment. So for now that is
everything about copilot related to
sustainability.
Uh I would like to invite you to watch
another sustainability session because
in this V center launch event we have
eight sessions completely related to
sustainability and thank you for
watching this video.